Tēlemachos Alaveras Papers and Nea Poreia Archives, 1989-2010: Finding Aid C1408
Manuscripts Division
- Series 2: Nea Poreia Archives, 1918-2009; 43 boxes
  - Subseries 2A: Nea Poreia Journal, 1957-2009; 19 boxes
    - Nea Poreia, 441-442, 1991; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 4)
      Published in November-December 1991. Includes autograph manuscripts and some page proofs.
    - Nea Poreia, 443-446, 1990-1992; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 5)
      Published in January-April 1992. Includes originals and photocopies of autograph manuscripts; typescripts; and page proofs with autograph manuscript annotations.
    - Nea Poreia, 447-449, 1992; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 6)
      Published in May-July 1992. Includes originals and photocopies of autograph manuscripts and typescripts.
    - Nea Poreia, 450-452, 1992; 1 folder (Box 53, Folder 7)
      Published in August-October 1992. Includes page proofs with handwritten annotations; originals and photocopies of autograph manuscripts and typescripts.
    - Nea Poreia, 453-454, 1985-1992; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 1)
      Published in November-December 1992. Includes originals and photocopies of autograph manuscripts and typescripts; as well as page proofs with handwritten annotations.
    - Nea Poreia, 455-457/201, 1986-1993; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 2)
      Published in January-March 1993. Includes originals and photocopies of autograph manuscripts; a few photocopies of typescripts; and page proofs with handwritten annotations.
    - Nea Poreia, 458-460/202, 1987-1993; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 3)
      Published in April-June 1993. Includes autograph manuscript drafts; typescripts; and page proofs with handwritten corrections.
    - Nea Poreia, 461-463/203, 1993; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 4)
      Published in July-September 1993. Includes autograph manuscripts; originals and photocopies of typescripts; and page proofs with handwritten corrections.
    - Nea Poreia, 464-466/204, 1993; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 5)
      Published in October-December 1993. Includes autograph manuscripts; typescripts; and page proofs with handwritten corrections.
    - Nea Poreia, 467-470/205, 1992-1994; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 6)
      Published in January-April 1994. Includes originals and photocopies of typescripts with handwritten corrections; autograph manuscripts; and page proofs.
    - Nea Poreia, 471-473/206, 1994; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 7)
      Published in May-July 1994. Includes originals and photocopies of autograph manuscripts and typescripts; as well as page proofs with handwritten annotations.
    - Nea Poreia, 474-476/207, 1989-1994; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 1)
      Published in August-October 1994. Includes originals and photocopies of autograph manuscripts and typescripts; and page proofs with handwritten annotations.
    - Nea Poreia, 477-478/208, 1989-1993; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 2)
      Published in November-December 1994. Includes autograph manuscripts; typescripts; and page proofs.
    - Nea Poreia, 479-482/209, 1979-1995; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 3)
      Published in January-April 1995. Includes originals and photocopies of autograph and typed manuscripts; and page proofs, some with handwritten annotations.
    - Saranta chronia Nea Poreia, Special Issue, 4, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 55, Folder 4-5)
      Published in October 1995. Includes page proofs with handwritten annotations; originals and photocopies of autograph manuscripts and typescripts of the special issue 4 with the indeces of the fourth decade 1985-1994 (Euretēria Neas Poreias, Tetartē dekaetia, 1985-1994).
    - Saranta chronia Nea Poreia, Special issue, 4, 1994-1995; 5 folders (Box 56, Folder 1-5)
    - Saranta chronia Nea Poreia, Special issue, 4, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 57, Folder 1-2)
    - Nea Poreia, 491-493/213, undated; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Published in January-March 1996. Includes originals and photocopies of autograph manuscripts and typescripts.
    - Nea Poreia, 494-496/214, 1996; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Published in April-June 1996. Includes originals and photocopies of autograph manuscripts and typescripts; and page proofs.
    - Nea Poreia, 497-499/215, 1996; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Published in July-September 1996.
    - Nea Poreia, 500-502/216, 1996; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 6)
      Published in October-December 1996.
    - Nea Poreia, 503-505/217, 1949-1997; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 7)
      Published in January-March 1997.
    - Nea Poreia, 506-508/218, 1987-1997; 2 folders (Box 58, Folder 1-2)
      Published in April-June 1997.
    - Nea Poreia, 509-511/219, 1997; 1 folder (Box 58, Folder 3)
      Published in July-September 1997.
    - Nea Poreia, 512-514/220, 1997; 1 folder (Box 58, Folder 4)
      Published in October-December 1997.
    - Methorios, Special issue, 5, 1992-1998; 4 folders (Box 58, Folder 5-8)
      Published in June 1998.
    - Nea Poreia, 515-517/221, 1997; 1 folder (Box 58, Folder 9)
      Published in January-March 1998.
    - Nea Poreia, 518-520/222, undated; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 1)
      Published in April-June 1998.
    - Nea Poreia, 521-523/223, 1994-1998; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 2)
      Published in July-September 1998.
    - Nea Poreia, 524-526/224, 1998; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 3)
      Published in Otober-December 1998. Includes autograph manuscripts and typescripts with handwritten annotations.
    - Nea Poreia, 527-529/225, 1997-1999; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 4)
      Published in January-March 1999.
    - Nea Poreia, 530-532/226, 1998-1999; 2 folders (Box 59, Folder 5-6)
      Published in April-June 1999.
    - Nea Poreia, 533-535/227, 1999; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 7)
      Published in July-September 1999.
    - Nea Poreia, 536-538/228, 1999; 1 folder (Box 59, Folder 8)
      Published in October-December 1999.
    - Nea Poreia, 539-541/229, 1998-1999; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 1)
      Published in January-March 2000. Includes autograph manuscripts; typescripts with handwritten corrections; and page proofs.
    - Nea Poreia, 542-544/230, 2000; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 2)
      Published in April-June 2000.
    - Nea Poreia, 545-547/231, 2000; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 3)
      Published in July-September 2000.
    - Nea Poreia, 548-550/232, 1991-2000; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 4)
      Published in October-December 2000.
    - Nea Poreia, 551-553/233, 2000-2001; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 5)
      Published in January-March 2001.
    - Nea Poreia, 554-556/234, 2000-2001; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 6)
      Published in April-June 2001.
    - Nea Poreia, 557-560/235, 2001; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 7)
      Published in July-October 2001.
    - Nea Poreia, 561-563/236, 2001; 1 folder (Box 60, Folder 8)
      Published in October-December 2001.
    - Nea Poreia, 563-565/237, 2000-2001; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 1)
      Published in January-March 2002.
    - Nea Poreia, 566-568/238, 2002; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 2)
      Published in April-June 2002.
    - Nea Poreia, 569-571/239, 1999-2002; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 3)
      Published in July-September 2002.
    - Nea Poreia, 572-574/240, undated; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 4)
      Published in October-December 2002.
    - Nea Poreia, 575-577/241, undated; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 5)
      Published in January-March 2003. Includes autograph manuscripts and typescripts with handwritten corrections. There is also a floppy disk of Sōtērēs Sarakēs's poems, which are included in this issue.
    - Nea Poreia, 578-580/242, 2001-2002; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 6)
      Published in April-June 2003.
    - Nea Poreia, 581-583/243, 2002; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 7)
      Published in July-September 2003.
    - Nea Poreia, 584-586/244, 2003; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 8)
      Published in October-December 2003.
    - Nea Poreia, 587-589/245, undated; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 9)
      Published in January-March 2004.
    - Nea Poreia, 590-592/246, undated; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 10)
      Published in April-June 2004. Included are autograph manuscripts; typescripts; and three floppy disks.
    - Nea Poreia, 593-595/247, 2002; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 1)
      Published in July-September 2004.
    - Nea Poreia, 596-598/248, 2003-2004; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 2)
      Published in October-December 2004.
    - Nea Poreia, 599-601, 2004; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 3)
      Published in January-March 2005.
    - Nea Poreia, 602-604, 2004-2005; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 4)
      Published in April-June 2005.
    - Nea Poreia, 605-607, 2005; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 5)
      Published in July-September 2005.
    - Nea Poreia, 608-610, 2005; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 6)
      Published in October-December 2005.
    - Nea Poreia, 611-613, undated; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 7)
      Published in January-March 2006.
    - Nea Poreia, 614-616, 2006; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 8)
      Published in April-June 2006.
    - Nea Poreia, 617-619, 2006; 1 folder (Box 62, Folder 9)
      Published in July-September 2006.
    - Apo to deutero miso tou 20ou aiōna, Special issue, 6, 2006; 6 folders (Box 63, Folder 1-6)
      Published in September 2006.
    - Apo to deutero miso tou 20ou aiōna, Special issue, 6, 2006; 6 folders (Box 64, Folder 1-6)
    - Nea Poreia, 620-622, 2000-2006; 1 folder (Box 65, Folder 1)
      Published in October-December 2006.
    - Nea Poreia, 623-625, 2007; 1 folder (Box 65, Folder 2)
      Published in January-March 2007.
    - Nea Poreia, 626, 2006-2009; 5 folders (Box 65, Folder 3-7)
      Published in April-June 2007/February 2009. This is the last issue of the magazine Nea Poreia.
    - Nea Poreia, Miscellaneous, 1954-2006; 6 folders (Box 66, Folder 1-6)
  - Subseries 2B: Nea Poreia Published and Unpublished Material, 1952-2001; 8 boxes
    Consists of autograph and typed manuscripts of poems, short novels, essays, or translations in Greek that were submitted for publication to Nea Poreia by several Greek authors. Included are published and unpublished writings. There are also several works, which are uncertain whether or not they have been published in Nea Poreia.
    This subseries has been arranged roughly chronologically.
    - Published and Unpublished, 1948-1959; 1 folder (Box 66, Folder 7)
      Included are autograph manuscripts and typescripts of drafts of poems and of some short novels by several authors. Handwritten note on the discarded folder stated that this material is published and unpublished.
    - Published and Unpublished, 1960-1968; 1 folder (Box 67, Folder 1)
      Includes autograph manuscripts and typescripts of short essays, novels, and poems by several Greek authors to be published in Nea Poreia.
    - Published and Unpublished, 1976-1981; 1 folder (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Published and Unpublished, undated; 1 folder (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Unpublished, 1953-1985; 1 folder (Box 67, Folder 4)
      Alaveras's note on the discarded folders stated that this material has been unpublished. Included also is incoming correspondence.
    - Unpublished, 1980-1985; 1 folder (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Unpublished, 1985-1997; 1 folder (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Unpublished, 1990-1995; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Unpublished, 1996; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Unpublished, 1997-1999; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Unpublished, 1999; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Unpublished, 1999-2009; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Unpublished, 2000-2001; 1 folder (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Unpublished, 2001-2002; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Unpublished, 2003-2010; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Unpublished, undated; 5 folders (Box 69, Folder 3-7)
    - Unpublished, undated; 5 folders (Box 70, Folder 1-5)
    - Unpublished, undated; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Uncertain whether or not they have been published in Nea Poreia, 1947-1989; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 2)
      Includes autograph manuscripts and typescripts of poems and short novels in Greek that were intended to be published in the journal Nea Poreia. It is uncertain whether or not these works have been published. There is also incoming correspondence.
    - Uncertain whether or not they have been published in Nea Poreia, 1970-1972; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Uncertain whether or not they have been published in Nea Poreia, 1973-1988; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Uncertain whether or not they have been published in Nea Poreia, 1986-1990; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Uncertain whether or not they have been published in Nea Poreia, 1989-1990; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Uncertain whether or not they have been published in Nea Poreia, 1990-2007; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Uncertain whether or not they have been published in Nea Poreia, undated; 4 folders (Box 72, Folder 2-5)
    - Uncertain whether or not they have been published in Nea Poreia, undated; 2 folders (Box 73, Folder 1-2)
  - Subseries 2C: Nea Poreia Publications. Thessalonikē, 1918-2003; 10 boxes
    This subseries includes autograph and typescripts drafts, as well as galley proofs of writings of several Greek authors.
    This subseries has been arranged in an alphabetical order by the last name of the author. In the case of more than one work by the same author then the arrangement has been made by a chronological order.
    - Alavera, Roula. Mia hēmeromēnia palia, 1974; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Alavera, Roula. Akēdia, 1983-1999; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 4)
      Includes an interview (February 25, 1997); a private agreement with the artist Giannēs Tseklenēs; a typescript of a presentation to an unidentified symposium; and a book review of Akēdia.
    - Alavera, Roula. Akēdia, undated; 1 box (Box 82)
    - Alavera, Roula. Pithanē apokalypsē tōra. Henos David aprosdioristou, 1988; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Anagnōstopoulou, Myrtō. To chroniko tōn hypodoriōn gegonotōn, 1995; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Antōniadēs, Vyrōn. Analōsē, 1985; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 7)
      Includes autogrpah manuscript drafts and page proofs.
    - Antōniou, Antōnēs. Ekeinos kai ho allos, 1987; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 8)
      Includes typescripts and page proofs.
    - Antōniou, Antōnēs. Kaleidoskopio. Poiēmata, 1987; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 9)
      Includes autograph manuscript drafts and page proofs.
    - Bakirtzēs, Ch. (Charalampos). Aēdia kai archaiologia, 1970; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 10)
      Includes two printed copies of Bakirtzēs's essay regarding Alaveras's book Hodostrōtēras.
    - Bakirtzēs, Ch. (Charalampos). Peza keimena me titlo archaiologikai meletai, 1978; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Charēs, Petros. Neoellēnikos kritikos logos, circa 1985; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Constantios I, Patriarch of Constantinople. Kōnstantinias palaia te kai neōtera, ētoi Perigraphē Kōnstantinoupoleōs, 1979; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Dalias, Chrēstos. Hēmerologia, 1982; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 3)
      Includes typescripts with handwritten notes.
    - Dalias, Chrēstos. Unidentified, 1982; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 4)
      Includes four notebooks, only one of those is dated 1982; Alaveras's handwritten note on the discarded envelope stated: "Loutrakiou" and "Oute kryo oute zestē."
    - Dalias, Chrēstos. Paraplērōmatika, 1983; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 5)
      Includes autograph manuscripts and page proofs.
    - Dalias, Chrēstos. Ta hepomena, 1985; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 6)
      Includes six spiral notebooks; page proofs; and autograph manuscripts.
    - Dalias, Chrēstos. Ta hepomena, 1985; 2 folders (Box 75, Folder 1-2)
    - Dalias, Chrēstos. Dasos 1 & Dasos 2, undated; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 3)
      Includes two notebooks with autograph manuscript drafts and page proofs.
    - Dalias, Chrēstos. Spiral, undated; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 4)
      Includes page proofs and one spiral notebook.
    - Dalias, Chrēstos. Unidentified, undated; 4 folders (Box 75, Folder 5-8)
      Includes page proofs of two unidentified works by Dalias and twelve spiral notebooks. There is also a biographical statement and a review of his work.
    - Dalias, Chrēstos. Unidentified, undated; 3 folders (Box 76, Folder 1-3)
    - Dalias, Chrēstos. Bibliography, undated; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Delios, Giōrgos. Pezographia, poiēsē, kritikē kai dokimiographia tēs Thessalonikēs, 1970; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 5)
      This work was published by Nea Poreia: Logotechnia tēs Thessalonikēs 3 (June 1988). Includes carbon typescripts dated 1970, according to Alaveras's handwritten note.
    - Gounarē, Maria. Apoēchoi. Thessalonikē, 1993; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Gounarē, Maria. Axechōristes, 1991; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Hofmannsthal, Hugo von. Mikra dramata kai prozes, tr. Dēmētrēs St. Dēmou, undated; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Kentrou-Agathopoulou, Maria. Anastasēs Vistōnitēs. "Tephres." Poiēmata, 1980; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 9)
      Includes typescripts of an essay.
    - Kōnstantinos, V. Erōs en kindynō, 1994; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 10)
      Includes page proofs. V. Kōnstantinos is the literary nickname of Kōnstantinos Vassēs.
    - Lampele, Phoula. Ho philos mou o Giozeph, 1992; 2 folders (Box 77, Folder 1-2)
    - Lamprellēs, Dēmētrēs N. Esoptros. Poiēmata, 1982; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 3)
      Includes page proofs and typescripts.
    - Lamprellēs, Dēmētrēs N. Ho diskos me ta stigmata. Poiēmata., 1990-1991; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Makariou, Maria. Pinakes periechomenōn tōn periodikōn Makedonika Grammata (1922-1924) kai Morphes, undated; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 5)
      Includes page proofs. It was published in 1988.
    - Makrēs, Solōn. To mati tou Polyphēmou, 1996; 3 folders (Box 77, Folder 6-8)
    - Makrēs, Solōn. To mati tou Polyphēmou, 1996; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Markas, Kōstas. Schedon erōtika, 1984; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 2)
      Includes page proofs and typescripts with handwritten editions.
    - Meralidou, Phila. To pouli kai to synnepho, 1983; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Merkenidou, Helenē. Hē nostalgia. Mia droserē mēchanē tōn Odysseōn, 1985; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Merkenidou, Helenē. Anterōs hē erēmia, 1990; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Merkenidou, Helenē. Avessalōm, Titania, Kommodos, Danaos, Sylphida, Saoul. Poiēmata, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Molyvitēs, Giōrgos. Kryvoun vasana tou kochyliou ta matia. Poiēmata, 1994; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 7)
      Includes page proofs and photocopies of autograph manuscripts by Molyvitēs.
    - Mourelos, Giōrgos I. Hē paraxenē ventagia, 1984; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Nikēphorou, Tolēs. Xenes chōres. Poiēmata, 1991; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Nikēphorou, Tolēs. To diplo alpha tēs agapēs, 1994; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Palla, Maria. Ta peza, 2002-2003; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 11)
      Includes one complete bound typescript with handwritten corrections and one unbound copy of page proofs.
    - Pallas, Theodōros. Poiēmata. Thessalonikē, 1989-1990; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 12)
      Includes autograph manuscripts. It is uncertain whether or not it has been published.
    - Panerēs, I.P. Poiēmata (1953-1990), 1991; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Papakōnstantinou, Dēmētrēs. Mikrē periēgēsē. Epimeleia ekdoseōn Nea Poreia. Thessalonikē, 1996; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 2)
      Includes page proofs and a notebook.
    - Polyzōidēs, Stauros K. Stigmiotypa apo prosōpikes anamnēseis tou Staurou K. Polyzōidē, 1991-1994; 2 folders (Box 79, Folder 3-4)
      Includes page proofs and typescripts with handwritten emendations. There are aslo two incoming letters.
    - Polyzos, Achilleas. Orycheio thanatou, undated; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Samaras, Zoé. To perasma tēs Eurydikēs, 1997; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Spentzēs, Petros. En opsei, 1984; 2 folders (Box 79, Folder 7-8)
    - Themelēs, Geōrgios. To peristeri kai ta hephta anastasima thaumata, 1977; 1 box (Box 82)
    - Thoividopoulos, Dēmētrēs. Dexiōsis, 1982; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Tsaloumas, Dimitris. To vivlio tōn epigrammatōn, 1982; 2 folders (Box 80, Folder 2-3)
      Includes page proofs, typescripts and two outgoing letters to Tēlemachos Alaveras.
    - Tsaloumas, Dimitris. Ho gios tou kyr Sakē, 1984; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Tsaloumas, Dimitris. Contemporary Australian Poetry selected and translated by Dimitris Tsaloumas (Synchronē australianē poiēsē / anthologēsē, metaphrasē, scholia Dēmētrē Tsalouma), 1985; 2 folders (Box 80, Folder 5-6)
      Includes page proofs of the book which was co-published by Nea Poreia and the University of Queensland Press with the assistance of the Literature Board of the Australian Council.
    - Tsaloumas, Dimitris. Contemporary Australian Poetry selected and translated by Dimitris Tsaloumas (Synchronē australianē poiēsē / anthologēsē, metaphrasē, scholia Dēmētrē Tsalouma), 1984-1986; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 1)
      Includes extensive incoming and outgoing correspondence between Tsaloumas and Alaveras; with the University of Queensland Press; and with the Literature Board of the Australian Council.
    - Tsoukalas, Geōrgios. Historiogeōgraphikē perigraphē tēs eparchias Philippoupoleōs, 1980; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Vamvakas, Petros K. Sēmeiōseis tou stratiōtikou mou viou, 1918-1990; 2 folders (Box 81, Folder 3-4)
      Includes photocopies of Vamvakas's notebook with autograph corrections by Alaveras; a small diary notebook dated 1918-1921; two cartes postales with handwritten captions by Vamvakas dated 1921; one black-and-white slide; a carbon copy of a military document dated 1921; a carbon copy of a letter signed by Vamvakas; a typescript of Vamvakas's essay about his book Peri apeleutherōseōs tēs dytikēs Thrakēs; and autograph manuscript notes by Alaveras.
    - Vasilopoulou, Sophia. Thema chronou, 1993; 2 folders (Box 81, Folder 5-6)
    - Vazra, Persa. Mia epimonē anoixē [A persistent spring], 1987; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Vazra, Persa. Ennea parentheseis kai kathetes meres, 1994; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2D: Associations-Organizations, 1962-2005; 4 boxes
    This subseries consists of autograph manuscripts and typescripts, as well as printed material regarding several literary organizations.
    This subseries has been organized in an alphabetical order.
    - Ethnikē Hetairia tōn Hellēnōn Logotechnōn [National Society of Greek Writers], 1967; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Ethnikē Vivliothēke tēs Helladas [National Library of Greece], 2004-2005; 4 folders (Box 83, Folder 2-5)
      Includes copies of the publications catalog of the National Libary of Greece.
    - Ethnikos Syllogos Phoitētōn Philosophikēs [National Student Club of Philosophy], undated; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Hetairia Logotechnōn Thessalonikēs [Thessalonikē Writer's Association], 1962-2003; 3 boxes
      - By-laws; Directory, 1962-2003; 2 folders (Box 83, Folder 7-8)
      - Proposals to the Prime Minister and Minister of Culture of Greece; Annual Reports, 1969-1993; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 9)
      - Proposals to the Prime Minister and Minister of Culture of Greece; Annual Reports, 1981-2001; 3 folders (Box 84, Folder 1-3)
      - Minutes, 1962-1984; 2 folders (Box 85, Folder 1-2)
      - Panellēnio Logotechniko Synedrio [National Literary Conference], 1981 December; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 4)
        Includes autograph manuscripts and typescripts of the presentations of the Panellēnio Logotechniko Synedrio [National Literary Conference] on the "Writing Rights"; correspondence with the Ministry of Culture and other literary organizations; the by-laws of the Association; list of the members; proceedings of the Board annual reports; brochures; and printed invitations.
      - Printed Invitations-Programs, 1981-1994; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Hetairia Syngrapheōn [Hellenic Author's Society], 2003-2004; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 6)